Enough's enough, Curly. You can't eat the Venetian blinds, I just got them.
好了，克力,够了。你总不能把百叶 窗吃了吧，我可是星期三才把它装上。
Down the hatch.
喝一杯吧
- She's no good. - What can I tell you?
- 她并不好 - 我该怎么跟你说呢？
When you're right, you're right. And you're right.
当你是正确的时候，你就是对的。 那这一次，你是对的。
I'll pay you the rest next week. We only caught 60 tons of skipjack.
剩下的我会下个星期付给你。 我们只捕到了60吨飞鱼。
They pay less for skipjack than albacore tuna.
而且，飞鱼比金枪鱼赚得少。
I only brought it up to illustrate a point. I don't want your last dime.
我只是想让你明白这一点。我不会拿走你 最后的一毛钱，我不是你想得那种人。
- Thank you, Mr Gittes. - Call me Jake. Careful driving home.
- 谢谢你，吉特斯先生 - 有事打电话。开车回家小心点。
Mrs Mulwray is waiting for you, with Mr Walsh and Mr Duffy.
默瑞夫人正在等你，还有沃尔什先生和达菲先生
Mrs Mulwray, may I present Mr Gittes.
默瑞夫人，我来给你介绍下吉特斯先生
- Mrs Mulwray, how do you? - Mr Gittes.
- 默瑞夫人，你好 - 吉特斯先生
What seems to be the problem?
出了什么问题吗？
My husband... I believe is seeing another woman.
My husband... I believe 是我的丈夫…… 我觉得他在跟另一个女人幽会
No... really? I am sorry.
-哦……真的吗？ -恐怕是   -很抱歉是这样。
Mr Gittes, do you think we could discuss this alone?
吉特斯先生，我们能单独谈谈吗？
I'm afraid not. These are my operatives, -
恐怕不行，他们是我的侦探……
- and at some point they'll have to assist me.
有些时候，他们得帮我
- I can't do everything myself. - Of course not.
- 有些事情我自己可做不来 - 这很正常
What makes you certain that your husband is involved with someone?
是什么让你确信你丈夫跟别人有瓜葛？
A wife can tell.
作为妻子，我能感觉得到
- Do you love your husband? - Yes, of course.
-默瑞夫人，你爱你的丈夫吗？ -是的，当然
Then go home and forget everything.
那就回家然后把这些都忘了吧。
I'm sure he loves you too. Do you know the expression: Let sleeping dogs lie?
我肯定他也爱你。 知道这句话吗：别自找麻烦？
- You're better off not knowing. - I have to know.
- 你最好还是什么都不要知道 - 我一定要知道
Very well.
那好吧
- What is your husband's first name? - Hollis. Hollis Mulwray.
- 你丈夫叫什么名字？ - 霍利斯。霍利斯 默瑞。
- Water and Power? - He's chief engineer.
- 水利能源部的？ - 他是总工程师
Chief engineer?
总工程师？
This type of investigation can be hard on your pocketbook.
这种类型的调查可能会花去不少钱
- It takes time... - Money doesn't matter to me.
- 我们需要时间…… - 钱对我来说不是问题
Okay, we'll see what we can do.
好吧，我们……看看能干点什么。
Today you can hop a streetcar, and in 25 minutes, you end up in the Pacific.
现如今，你可以跳上一辆电车， 25分钟以后，就到终点太平洋
You can swim in it and fish in it, but you can't drink it.
你可以在那儿游泳，钓鱼 不过那个水可不能喝
You can't irrigate an orange grove with it.
不能用它浇灌桔子林
We live next door to the ocean, but we also live on the edge of a desert.
请记得，虽然我们生活在海洋附近， 可同时，我们也生活在沙漠的边缘
Los Angeles is a desert community.
洛杉矶是一个沙漠地区
Beneath this building is a desert.
这座建筑之下的就是沙漠
Without water, the dust will rise up cover us as though we never existed.
如果没有水，沙子就会上升，覆盖我们 就像我们从来就没有存在过一样
The Alto Vallejo can save us from this.
这个艾尔透 瓦列霍计划能让我们避免这件事。
I suggest that 81/2 million dollars is a fair price to pay -
我认为为了让沙漠远离我们的街道 而不要覆盖它们...
- to keep the desert from our streets, and not on top of them.
...850万美元是一笔值得花的钱。
Mayor Bagby... Let's hear from all the departments again.
贝格柏市长……我们再来听听各部门的意见
We'd better take Water and Power first. Mr Mulwray?
我建议从水利能源部开始吧。 默瑞先生？
In case you've forgotten, over 500 died when the Van der Lip Dam gave way.
不知大家是否还记得，范德利普大坝 倒塌的时候，有500多人死亡
This shale is similar to the permeable shale in the Van der Lip disaster.
根据我们取得的样品，这种页岩跟 范德利普灾害中的渗透性页岩性质相似
It couldn't withstand that kind of pressure.
它承担不了那么大的水压
Now you propose another dirt-banked dam, -
而现在你们计划建造另外一个...
- with slopes of 21/2 to 1, 112 feet high, and a 12,000-acre water surface.
...坡度为2.5到1度，高112英尺，水表 面积12000英亩的泥土堤的大坝的话
Well, it won't hold. I won't build it, it's that simple.
它一定承受不了。 我是不会建的，就这么简单
I'm not going to make the same mistake twice.
我不想同样的错误犯两次
What the hell are you doing? Get those goddam things out of here!
你们到底在做什么？ 把这些该死的东西弄出去。
Tell me where to take them! You don't have an answer for that.
你告诉我把它们弄到哪儿去？！ 你自己都不知道该怎么办，是不是？
You steal water from the valley, ruin the grazing, starve the livestock...
你们把水从山谷里弄走了，你们毁了我们 的牧草，饿死了我们的牲畜……
Who's paying you to do that, Mulwray? That's what I want to know!
默瑞！谁指使你这么干的？ 这是我想知道的！
- Jeez, he was there all night. - That's right.
- 哎，他一个晚上都在那里 - 可不是
I had to go back three times to pick up the watches.
为了跟踪监视他，我不得不返回去三次
Yesterday he went to three reservoirs, a men's room, and the Pig & Whistle.
昨天他去了三个水库， 一个男人家里，还去了酒吧
The guy's got water on the brain.
那家伙八成脑子进水了
So what have you got?
你有什么消息？
- This? - They got into a terrific argument.
- 就这些？ - 他们争吵的很激烈，就在酒吧外面
- What about? - I don't know. The traffic was loud.
- 争论什么？ - 我不知道。过往车辆噪音太大。
I heard one thing though: "Apple core".
我就听见一个词“苹果核”
- Apple core? - Yeah.
- 苹果核？ - 嗯
- Is that what you spent the day doing? - You said to take pictures, so I did.
- 以这一天就干了这点儿活？ - 你说拍照片啊，我拍了
Let me explain something to you, Walsh.
沃尔什，我得给你解释一下
This business requires a certain amount of finesse.
这桩买卖需要耍些手段
- What is it, Sophie? - Duffy's on the phone.
- 什么事，苏菲？ - 达菲的电话
- Duff, where are you? - The buzzard's got a cute little twist.
- 达菲，你在哪儿？ - 我找到了。那个贪心的家伙跟个姑娘在一起。
- Slow down. Where are you? - They're in Echo Park, in a rowboat!
- 好，慢点说，你在哪儿？ - 他们在埃克公园，在划艇上。
Okay...
好的……
Echo Park. Water again.
埃克公园，又是水。
Okay, pal, let's have us a big smile.
来，伙计 笑一下
You'll love it.
你会喜欢的
When you get this much publicity, you're practically a movie star.
当你也得到这么多宣传时， 你也和电影明星了差不多了
- Look at that, Barn. - Yeah, the heat's murder.
- 看那个，贝恩。 - 是啊，太热的缘故
Fools' names and fools' faces.
白痴名字，白痴面孔
- What's that, pal? - You've got some way to make a living.
- 那是什么，伙计？ - 没什么   - 你找到了谋生的方法了？
- What do you do to make ends meet? - Mortgages. First National Bank.
- 哦？你怎么让收支平衡？ - 我在第一国家银行抵押部工作。
Did you foreclose on many families this week?
你这周是不是取消了很多家庭 赎回抵押的权利？
- We don't publish records in the paper. - Neither do I.
- 我们不会把记录在报纸上公布的， 这是我能告诉你的。   - 我也不会
- No, you have your press agent do it. - Is this bimbo a regular customer?
- 对，不过你让你的新闻代理帮你做 - 这个大蠢货是谁？是你们的常客吗？
I make an honest living. I help people when they're in a desperate situation.
你听着，我老老实实是挣钱， 我帮助那些绝望的人们
I don't kick families out of their houses like you bums at the bank do.
我不像你这废物在银行做的那样， 把人们从房子里赶出来
Maybe you'd like to go outside and discuss it. What do you think?
也许你想从理发椅上下来， 和我到外面谈谈谈。你觉得呢？
- Let me tell you about the guy... - I don't know how it got in the paper.
听我跟你说说这个家伙…… 我不知道怎么上的报纸，快得连我自己都不知道
- I make an honest living. - Of course you do.
- 做人要诚实。 - 你当然是。
Anyway, this guy got tired of screwing his wife.
不管怎样，这个家伙厌烦弄他的妻子了
So his friend says he should do what the Chinese do...
所以他的朋友说他应该像中国人那样做…
Duffy. Hey, Walsh! Sophie, go to the little girls' room for a minute.
-达菲，  -嗨，沃尔什。 -苏菲，先去洗手间呆一会儿
But Mr Gittes... Yes, Mr Gittes.
可是，吉特斯先生…… 是的，吉特斯先生
I want to tell you a story. There's a guy who's tired of screwing his wife...
听我说，我给你们讲个故事。有个家伙 厌倦于弄他的妻子了……
- Jake, there's a problem. - Wait a second.
- 伙计，有个问题 - 等会儿再说，先别着急
His friend says to do it like the Chinese do it. "How do the Chinese do it?"
他朋友告诉他像中国人那么做。 “中国人怎么做？”
'Well, first they screw a little bit, then they read a little Confucius, -
“这样，他先弄一会儿，然后读一下孔子的书……
- come back, screw a little bit more, then they stop again..."
……再回来，多弄一会，然后又停下来...
- Jake! - Walsh, just listen, you'll love this.
- 杰克！ - 沃尔什，好好听，你会喜欢的
'They go back and they screw a little bit more, -
他们再回来，再多弄一会儿…
- and then they contemplate the moon. It makes it more exciting."
然后他们出去，凝望月亮，这样更刺激
So now the guy goes home and starts screwing his own wife.
所以，现在这个家伙回家了， 开始弄他自己的妻子
So he screws her a little, then goes out of the room and reads Life magazine.
他弄一会儿，然后停下， 出去读一会儿生活杂志
He goes back in and screws her a bit, then goes out and smokes a cigarette.
然后他回来继续弄，然后他又说： “请原谅，亲爱的”。然后再出去，抽根烟
His wife is sore. So the next time he's going out to look at the moon she says:
他的妻子很恼火。当他再一次要出去看月亮 的时候，她就忍不住说：
"Hey, what's the matter with you? You're screwing just like a Chinaman!"
“喂，你到底怎么了？ 怎么象中国人那么干？”
Jesus, that Barney...
天哪，那个巴尼……
- Mr Gittes? - Yes.
- 吉特斯先生 - 是的
Do you know me?
你认识我吗？
Well... I think I would have remembered.
嗯……我觉得自己会记得的。
- Have we ever met? - Well, no.
- 我们见过面吗？ - 嗯，没有
- Never? - Never.
- 从来没有？ - 从来没有。
That's what I thought. I'm Mrs Evelyn Mulwray. Mr Mulwray's wife.
我也是这么想的。我是伊夫琳 默瑞夫人。 默瑞先生的妻子。
Not that Mulwray?
不是那个默瑞吧？
Yes, Mr Gittes. That Mulwray.
是的，吉特斯先生。就是那个默瑞。
And since you agree that we've never met before, -
既然你承认我们从来都没有见过……-
- you must also agree that I never hired you to spy on my husband.
你也一定同意，我从来都有雇过 你跟踪我的丈夫。
I see you like publicity, Mr Gittes.
我发现你很喜欢公众的注意，吉特斯先生
Well, you're going to get it.
你会得到的
There's been some misunderstanding. There's no need to get tough with me...
等一下，这儿有点误会。 没必要跟我这么强硬……
I don't get tough with anyone. My lawyer does.
我不会对任何人强硬。 我的律师会这样
Here's something for you, Mr Gittes.
有东西要给你，吉特斯先生
I suppose we'll be hearing from your attorney.
希望你的律师会跟我们联系
- Mr Mulwray? - He's not in, Mr...?
-默瑞先生在吗？ - 他不在，你是…  -吉特斯
- May I ask what it's regarding? - It's personal. Has he been gone long?
- 可以问一下有什么事吗？ - 私人事情。他走了很久吗？
- Since lunch. - Gee whiz, and I'm late.
- 午饭的时候走的 - 唉，我来晚了
- He was expecting you? - 15 minutes ago. I'll go in and wait.
- 他在等你吗？ - 15分钟前。我为什么不进去进去等他呢。
Sir!
先生！
Could I help you? Russ Yelburton, deputy chief.
我能帮你吗？我是阿什.伊尔伯特，副总
J.J. Gittes. It's not a departmental matter.
我是杰克.吉特斯. 不是关于部门的事.
- Would you care to wait in my office? - Certainly.
- 你介意在我的办公室等吗？ - 当然不
We're a bit nervous, with all this business in the papers -
对于报纸上，关于默瑞先生的事情……
- about Mr Mulwray. Right this way.
我们多少有点敏感。 这边走。
After you've worked with a man for a certain length of time, -
当你跟一个人一起工作一段时间以后……
- you come to know his habits and values.
你就会知道他的习惯和价值。
Either he's the kind who chases after women, or he isn't.
到底他是一个喜欢追求女人的人， 还是不是。
- Mulwray never even kids about it. - Maybe he takes it very seriously.
- 他甚至不开这方面的玩笑。 - 可能他对这事非常认真。
- Sit down. - No, thank you.
- 请坐。 - 不了，谢谢
- Where is he having lunch? - I'm sorry, I don't know.
- 你知道他去哪儿吃午饭？ - 很抱歉，我不知道。
- Well, tell him I'll be back. - I will.
- 那，跟他说我会回来。 - 我会的。
Do you mind if I take one of your cards, in case I have to get in touch with you?
-你介意我拿你一张名片吗，便跟你联系？ -请自便。   -谢谢。
- Mulvihill, what are you doing here? - They shut my water off. So what?
- 莫威黑尔, 你在这儿干吗？ - 他们把我的水停了。
How'd you find out? You don't drink it, you don't take a bath in it...
你怎么发现的？ 你也没喝水，也不在那儿洗澡……
They wrote you a letter... But then you'd have to be able to read.
他们给你写了一封信…… 那也要你识字才行啊。
Relax, glad to see you.
放松点，见到你很高兴。
- Do you know Claude Mulvihill? - I hope so, he's working for us.
- 你认识克劳德.莫威黑尔吗？? - 我想是的，他给我们工作。
- Doing what? - There's been threats to the reservoirs.
- 做什么? - 坦率地说，水库面临一些威胁.
- Any particular reason? - Rationing. The farmers are desperate.
- 有什么特殊的原因吗？? - 因为配给. 那些农民想要拼命。
- But the city needs drinking water. - Well, you're in luck.
- 不过城市需要饮用水. - 恩，你很幸运，有了莫威黑尔先生
When he was sheriff, the rum runners landed tons of booze on the beach -
他当治安官的时候, 那些朗姆酒经营商 放了成吨的酒在海滩上……
- and never lost a drop. He ought to be able to hold on to your water for you.
一滴都没丢过。 他应该可以帮你保存你的水。
J.J. Gittes to see Mr Mulwray.
我是杰克.吉特斯，来见默瑞先生
Please.
请进
You wait.
稍等
- Bad for glass. - Yeah, sure.
- 对玻璃不好. - 是的，当然.
Bad for the glass.
对玻璃不好.
- Mr Gittes. - Actually, I came to see your husband.
- 吉特斯. - 事实上，我来找你的丈夫
- Something to drink? - What are you having?
- 喝点什么？ - 你有什么？
- Iced tea. - That'll be fine, thank you.
- 冰茶 - 它就很好，谢谢。 - 两杯冰茶
My husband's at the office.
我丈夫在办公室。
Actually, he's not. And he's checked out of his apartment at the El Macondo.
事实上，他不在。而且他刚刚为在 El Macondo的公寓付了钱.
That's not his apartment.
那不是他的公寓.
Anyway, the point is, I'm not in business to be loved, -
总之，问题是 我不是在讨论爱的问题……
- but I am in business. Whoever set your husband up, set me up.
……可是我在做生意. 不管是谁， 他在把陷害你丈夫的时候，也陷害了我.
L.A. Is a small town. People talk. I don't want to become a local joke.
洛杉矶是一个小地方，大家传来传去。 我只想在这儿生活，不想变成本地的笑话。
You've talked me into it. I'll drop the lawsuit.
你说服我了。 我会撤消诉讼。
- What? - Let's just drop the whole thing.
- 什么? - 我会撤消诉讼，撤销一切。
- Sugar, lemon, or both? - Both... I don't want to drop it.
- 糖还是柠檬，还是两个都要? - 都要……莫瑞太太，我不想放弃。
I better talk to your husband.
我最好跟你丈夫谈谈。
Why? Hollis seems to think you're an innocent man.
为什么？霍利斯似乎也觉得你是无辜的。
I've been accused of a lot of things, but never that.
在莫瑞先生的事之前，我已经被控告过 很多事情，但从来没有这样的。
Someone's gone to a lot of trouble, and I intend to find out.
有人会有很多麻烦，不管诉讼不诉讼， 我想查清楚。
I'm not supposed to be the one caught with his pants down.
我可不想毫无防备的被人整。
Unless it's a problem, I'd like to talk to your husband.
-除非有什么问题，否则我想跟你丈夫谈谈 -这是个问题。
- May I speak frankly, Mrs Mulwray? - You may if you can, Mr Gittes.
- 我可以坦白说吗，默瑞夫人？ - 如果你能，当然可以
That little girlfriend. She was pretty, in a cheap sort of way, of course...
那个年轻的女朋友。很可爱，当然 某种程度上，不值钱……
She's disappeared. Maybe they disappeared together.
她失踪了。 也许他们一起失踪了。
- If they did, how does that affect you? - It's nothing personal.
- 如果他们真的消失了，那又关你什么事？ - 这并不一件私人的事情。莫瑞太太
It's very personal. It couldn't be more personal.
很完全是私事，不能比这再私人了。
- Is this an obsession with you? - Let's look at it this way...
- 你对这件事很着迷吗？ - 让我们这样...
This phoney broad, excuse the language, tells me she's you.
那个贱女人，请原谅我的用词， 跟我说她是你，然后雇佣了我。
Whoever put her up to it isn't after me, they're out to get your husband.
不管是谁让她干的，他的目的 不是对付我，而是你的丈夫。
If I can see him, I can help him.
如果我能见见他，我就能帮帮他。
- Did you talk to him this morning? - No.
- 你今天早上跟他谈过吗？ - 没有。
I went riding rather early.
我很早就去骑马了。
- It looks like you went quite a distance. - I was riding bareback.
- 你好像骑了很远 - 我没有用马鞍
You might try the Oak Pass or the Stone Canyon Reservoir.
你到橡树关口或者石头峡谷水库看看。
He often takes walks. Otherwise he'll be home by 6:30.
他经常在那散步。 要不然，6：30之前就回家了。
- I'll stop by. - Please call first.
- 我会再来。 - 事先打个电话。
Sorry, closed to public.
对不起，不对公众开放，先生
That's all right, officer...
我知道，警官……
Russ Yelburton, Deputy Chief of the department.
我是阿什 伊尔伯特，这个部的副总
Sorry, Mr Yelburton. Go on down.
抱歉，伊尔伯特先生。 过去吧。
- Gittes, get out before he sees you. - Loach, what's going on?
- 吉特斯，天哪，在他看见你之前快离开。 - 你说什么呢？发生什么事了？
- Hello, Jake. - Lou. How are you?
- 嗨，伙计。 - 嗨，你好吗？
Lousy cold I can't seem to shake, but otherwise I'm okay.
除了有点冷，其他还好。
- Summer colds are the worst. - Yeah, they are.
- 夏天的冷最讨厌了。 - 可不是嘛
- There's no smoking here. - We'll make an exception this time.
- 这儿不许抽烟，先生 - 没事，这次可以例外
I'll see he's careful with the matches and doesn't burn himself.
我会看着他，让他小心火柴，不要烧到自己
How'd you get past the guard?
你怎么让门卫放行的？
To tell you the truth, I lied a little.
说实话，我撒了一个小谎
- You look like you've done well. - I get by.
- 你看起来干的不错 - 马马虎虎
Sometimes it takes a man a while to find himself. Maybe you have.
有的时候人要找到自己需要花 一点时间。你也许做到了。
Yeah, going through other people's dirty linen.
呵呵，靠别人的家丑过日子
Tell me, you still putting Chinamen in jail for spitting in the laundry?
告诉我，你还是因为他们在洗衣店吐口水 而把中国佬送进监狱吗？
You're a little behind the times. They use steam irons now.
你有点跟不上时代了。 他们现在用蒸汽熨斗了。
And I'm out of Chinatown.
我现在也不在唐人街了。
- Since when? - Since I made lieutenant.
- 什么时候？ - 从我当上副手以后。
Congratulations.
祝贺你。
- What are you doing around here? - I'm looking for somebody.
- 你在这儿干吗？ - 找人。
- Hollis Mulwray. You seen him? - Yeah.
- 谁？ - 霍利斯 默瑞，你见过他吗？ - 见过
- I'd like to talk to him. - You'd like to talk to him...
- 我想跟他谈谈 - 你是想跟他谈谈……
You're welcome to try. There he is.
去试试吧。他在那儿
It looks like he was washed down the entire length of the run-off channel.
看起来他好像被冲着滑过了整个水道
- Could he swim? - Of course.
- 他会游泳吗？ - 当然
Obviously, the fall must have knocked him unconscious.
很显然，跌下去后他失去了知觉
Mrs Mulwray, this alleged affair your husband was having...
默瑞夫人，你丈夫那件所谓的风流韵事……
The publicity didn't make him morose or unhappy?
公开以后，没有让他郁闷或者不开心吗？
It didn't make him happy.
没有让他不高兴。
- He couldn't have taken his own life? - No.
- 他有没有可能自杀呢？ - 不会的。
Do you happen to know the name of the young lady in question?
莫瑞太太，你知不知道那个女人的名字？
- No. - Or where she might be?
- 不。 - 或者，她可能在什么地方？ -根本不知道
You and your husband never discussed her?
-你跟你丈夫没有讨论过她吗？
We did. He wouldn't tell me her name.
我们讨论过。 他不肯告诉我她的名字。
We quarrelled over her, of course. It came as a complete surprise to me.
我们当然因为这件事吵过架。 这对我来说完全在意料之外。
A complete surprise? I thought you hired a private investigator.
很意外？我以为你请了私家侦探的。
A private investigator?
私家侦探？
Mr Gittes.
吉特斯先生。
Yes, but I did that to put an end to a ridiculous rumour that had no basis.
是的，但我那么做只是为了让那些 没有根据的荒谬的谣传有个了结。
When did Mr Gittes inform you that the rumours had some foundation in fact?
吉特斯先生是什么时候告诉你 那些谣传是有事实依据的？
Just before the story broke in the papers.
就在这件事暴露在公众之前。
You wouldn't happen to know where I could find her... or her name?
-你不会碰巧知道知道我们在哪儿能找到她…… 或者她的名字？  --不知道
- No. - Of course not.
- 不知道。 当然不。
- Will you need me for anything else? - No, I don't think so.
- 你还有什么事需要帮忙的吗？ - 不，我想没有了。
If we need any more information we'll be in touch.
如果我们还需要什么信息的话， 会跟你联系的。
Of course you have my deepest sympathy.
我真的很同情你。
I'll see her to the car, Lou. I'll be right back.
卢，我把她送到车上，马上就回来。
- Jake, what's the story? - Take it easy.
- 伙计，怎么回事？ - 从容一点
We better do this in a hurry... Give us a little room!
我们得快点…… 请让一让！
You want a picture, guys? Here it is. "Gittes", two T's and an E.
你想要照片，伙计？拍我吧！ 我是吉特斯，两个T，一个E
Thank you for going along with me back there.
谢谢你一直陪我过来。
I just didn't want to explain anything. I'll send you a check.
我只是不想解释任何事情。 我会寄支票给你。
- A check? - To make it official that I've hired you.
- 支票？ - 让我雇佣你显得正式一点。
I'll have it this afternoon... Jake, what are you doing here?
我下午就办…… 伙计，你在这儿干吗？
It's my lunch hour, Morty. I thought I'd drop by and see who'd dropped dead.
莫蒂，现在是我的午饭时间。 我想过来看看是谁死了。
Middle of a drought, and the water commissioner drowns.
在闹干旱的时候， 一个水利能源部的委员淹死了。
- Only in L.A. - Looks pretty banged up.
- 这种事只会发生在洛杉矶 - 看起来摔得不轻
Well, it's a long fall.
可不是，那么高距离摔下来
So how are you doing, Morty?
你最近怎样，莫蒂？
Never better, except for this cough.
不能再好了，除了有点咳嗽
- You know me, Jake. - Yeah.
- 你了解我的，杰克 - 嗯
- So who have you got there? - Leroy Shuhardt. Local drunk.
- 这个是谁？ - 勒罗伊.舒哈特.一个本地的酒鬼
Used to hang around Ferguson's Alley.
以前常常在弗格森巷附近逛荡。
Quite a character. Lately he's been living in a downtown storm drain.
很是个人物。 最近他住在市区的排水沟里面。
Had a bureau dresser down there and everything.
那些衣柜啊什么的都被冲下来了
He drowned too.
他也是淹死的。
- Come again? - Got drunk. Passed out in the riverbed.
- 你说什么？ - 喝醉了。死在河床上
- The L.A. River? - Yeah, what's wrong with that?
- 洛杉矶河？ - 对啊，有什么不对吗？
- It's dry as a bone. - It's not completely dry.
- 它已经干涸了啊。 - 还有一点水。
He ain't gonna drown in a damp riverbed, no matter how soused he is.
不管他醉成什么样，也不会在一个 潮湿的河床里淹死啊。
We got water out of him. He drowned.
我们从他肚子里空出水了。 他是淹死的。
Hello.
你好。
Howdy. You were riding out here the other day, weren't you?
你好。 你有一天也到这儿了，是不是？
- Do you speak English? Habla Ingles? - Si.
- 你说英语吗？ 说英语? - 是的。
You were talking to a man a few days ago. He wore glasses...
你前几天跟一个男人说过话。 他戴眼镜……
- What did you talk about? - The water.
- 你介不介意我问一下你们在说什么？ - 水
- What about the water? - When it comes.
- 水的什么？ - 水从哪来。
- What did you tell him? - It comes in different parts of the river.
- 你怎么跟他说的？ - 它们从不同的地方流到河里。
Every night a different part.
每天晚上都是不同的地方。
Son of a bitch. Goddam Florsheim shoe.
婊子养的。 这该死的鞋子。
Hold it there, kitty cat.
嘿，站那儿别动。
Hello, Claude. Where'd you get the midget?
嗨，克劳德。 你从哪儿搞来的这个小东西？
You're a very nosy fellow. Know what happens to nosy fellows?
你是个爱管闲事的家伙。 知道爱管闲事的家伙下场是什么吗？
No? Wanna guess?
不知道？想猜猜吗？
No? Okay. They lose their noses.
不？好吧。 他们的鼻子都被割了。
Next time you lose the whole thing.
下一次的话，你什么东西都没了。
I'll cut it off and feed it to my goldfish. Understand?
我要把它割下来喂我的金鱼。明白了吗？
- Understand? - I understand.
- 明白了？ - 我明白。
So a contractor wants to build a dam and makes a few pay-offs. So what?
那承包人想修一个大坝赚点钱。 然后呢？
You can't nail Mulvihill. They'll claim you were trespassing.
你不能揭穿莫威黑尔. 他们会控告你非法侵入的。
I don't want Mulvihill. I want the big boys that are making the pay-offs.
我不想要莫威黑尔。 我想要的是那个赚钱的家伙。
- Then what'll you do? - Sue the shit out of them.
- 然后你干吗？ - 告得他们倾家荡产。
- What is it, Sophie? - A Miss Sessions is calling.
- 什么事，苏菲？ - 瑟莘小姐打来电话。
- Who? - Ida Sessions.
- 谁？ - 艾达 瑟莘。
Don't know her. Take a number.
不认识她。记下她的电话。
People like that will be having dinner with the judge who's trying the suit.
那样的人总是要跟负责案子的法官吃个饭。
I'm sorry. Miss Sessions insists.
很抱歉，她坚持要你听电话。
- She says you know her. - Okay.
- 她说你认识她。 - 好吧。
Hello, Miss Sessions. I don't believe we've had the pleasure.
你好，瑟莘女士。 我觉得我们不认识。
- Oh yes we have. Are you alone? - Isn't everyone?
- 哦，我们认识的。你一个人吗？ - 大家不都是吗？
What can I do for you?
有什么要我为你效劳的？
Well, I'm a working girl. I didn't come in to see you on my own.
这样，我只是个妓女。 上一次我不是以自己的身份来见的你。
- When did you come in? - I pretended to be Mrs Mulwray.
- 你什么时候来的？ - 我假装成默瑞夫人。
Shut the fuck up... Yes, I remember.
你们他妈的闭嘴 对，我记得。
- Is something wrong? - I was just checking with an associate.
- 有什么事吗？ - 我刚才在跟同事核对些事。
- Go on. - I never expected all this to happen.
- 请继续。 - 我没想到会发生莫瑞先生那样的事。
If it gets out, I want someone to know that I didn't know what would happen.
如果这件事最后暴露了，我只是想有人知道， 我并不知道会发生这些事情。
I understand. Who was your employer? It would be helpful to both of us.
我理解。是谁雇佣的你？ 告诉我对你我都有好处。
Oh, no. No.
哦，不。不。
What's your address? Maybe we could talk this over.
那你的地址呢？ 也许我们可以好好谈谈。
Just look in the obituary column of today's L.A. Post-Record.
看看今天洛杉矶邮政记录中的讣告栏。
You'll find one of those people.
你会从他们中找到一个。
Sure... How do you like them apples?
当然…… 你觉得这些家伙怎样？
Thank you for coming.
谢谢你过来。
- Yes, sir? - Drink?
- 是的，先生。 - 喝点什么？
Tom Collins with lime, not lemon.
汤姆 克林斯，加酸橙，不要柠檬
I got your check in the mail.
我收到了你随信寄过来的支票。
- As I said, I was very grateful. - I'm afraid that's not good enough.
- 像我说的，我真的很感激。 - 恐怕，这样还不够好。
- How much would you like? - Oh, stop it. The money's fine.
- 你想要多少钱？ - 哦，别说这个。钱已经够了。你很慷慨。
But I think you short-changed me on the story.
-但是我觉得在这个故事你没有全告诉我。 -我有吗？- 我认为是这样
Something else besides the death of your husband was bothering you.
除了你丈夫的死以外， 还有别的事情在烦着你。
- You were upset, but not that upset. - Don't tell me how I feel.
- 你很烦，但不是为那事烦 - 不用告诉我我自己的感觉是什么。
Sorry.
抱歉。
You sue me, your husband dies, you drop the lawsuit like a hot potato.
你起诉我，你丈夫死了 你又像丢掉烫手山芋一样撤销了控诉
All of it quicker than the wind from a duck's ass. Excuse me...
这一切比鸭子放屁来的还快。 原谅我的用词……
- Then you ask me to lie to the police. - It wasn't much of a lie.
- 然后你让我向警察撒谎。 - 并不完全是谎话。
If he was killed, it was. This could look like a pay-off to withhold evidence.
如果你的丈夫是被谋杀的，那就是。 这可以看作是隐藏证据的报酬。
But he wasn't killed.
但是他并不是被谋杀的。
Mrs Mulwray, I think you're hiding something.
默瑞夫人，我觉得你在隐藏些什么。
I suppose I am. Actually, I knew about the affair.
我想是的。 事实上，我知道他跟那个女人的事。
- How did you find out? - My husband.
- 你怎么发现的？ - 是我丈夫。
He told you? And you weren't in the least bit upset?
他告诉你的？ 难道你都没有一丁点的不高兴吗？
I was grateful.
我很感激。
- You'll have to explain that. - Why?
- 莫瑞太太，你得解释一下。 - 为什么？
When a wife tells me she's happy that her husband is cheating on her, -
一个妻子跟我说，她因为自己的丈夫 背叛了她而感到高兴……
- it runs contrary to my experience.
……这跟我的经验完全相反。除非……
- Unless what? - She was cheating on him.
- 除非什么？ - 她也背叛了他。
Were you?
是吗？
I dislike the word "cheat".
我不喜欢“背叛”这个词
Did you have affairs? Did he know about it?
-你有私情吗？  -吉特斯先生 他知道吗？
I wouldn't run home and tell him whenever I'd been to bed with another.
我不会跑到家告诉他到底 什么时候我在跟别人上床。
- Anything else you want to know? - Where were you when Hollis died?
- 你还想知道别的什么事情吗？ - 你丈夫死的时候你在哪儿？
- I can't tell you. - You don't know?
- 我不能告诉你。 - 你意思是你不知道你在哪儿？
- You were seeing someone too.
- 你也在跟别人幽会。
- For very long? - I don't see anyone for very long.
- 很久吗？ - 我不会跟任何人一起很久。
It's difficult for me.
这对我来说很困难。
Now, I think you know all you need know about me.
现在，我想你应该知道了所有 你想知道的关于我的事。
I didn't want publicity. I didn't want to go into all of this then, or now.
我当时并不想公开，也不想搅进 这些事情中来。现在也是。
Is that all?
够了吗？
Oh, by the way... What does this "C" stand for?
哦，等等…… 这个“C”是什么意思？
Cross.
克罗斯。
- That's your maiden name? - Yes. Why?
- 你的娘家姓? - 是的，怎么了？
No reason.
没什么。
- You must have had a reason to ask. - No, I'm just a snoop.
- 总有一个要问的原因吧。 - 没有，只是随便问问。
No, I have my own car. The Packard.
不，我自己有车。The Packard.
Wait a minute, sonny. I think you better come with me.
等一下，宝贝。 我觉得你最好跟我走。
There's nothing more to say. Get my car, please.
为什么？没什么好说的了。 麻烦你把我的车取过来。
Okay, but in case you're interested, your husband was murdered.
好吧，回家吧。也许你有兴趣的。 你丈夫是被谋杀的，
Someone's been dumping thousands of tons of water from the reservoirs, -
有人每天从水库排放掉上千吨的水……
- and we're supposedly in a drought. He found out about it and he was killed.
而期望我们闹旱灾。 他发现了这件事，所以他被杀了。
There's a drowned drunk. Involuntary manslaughter, if anyone took the time.
有一个被淹死的醉汉。如果有人刚巧在 那个时间出现的话，就会意外的丧命。
It seems like half the city is trying to cover it up, which is fine by me, -
看起来有一半的人都试图掩饰这件事， 对我来说没什么，
- but I goddam near lost my nose.
莫瑞太太，可我却差点因此丢了鼻子。
And I like it. I like breathing through it.
可我喜欢我的鼻子。 而且我喜欢用它呼吸。
And I still think that you're hiding something.
而且我仍然认为你在隐瞒些什么。
Mr Gittes...
吉特斯先生……
J.J. Gittes to see Mr Yelburton.
我是J. J. 吉特斯，来找伊尔伯特先生。
Mr Yelburton will be busy for some time.
伊尔伯特先生在忙
Well, it's my lunch hour. I can wait.
恩，反正是我的午饭时间。我可以等。
He's liable to be tied up indefinitely.
他那个时候可能也忙不完。
I take a long lunch hour. All day, sometimes.
我的午饭时间很长。 有的时候，甚至一天
- Noah Cross worked for the company? - Yes... No.
- 诺亚 克罗斯曾经在这儿工作？ - 是的……不。
- Did he or didn't he? - He owned it.
- 干过还是没有？ - 他曾经拥有它。
- He owned the water department? - Yes.
- 他拥有整个水利部门？ - 是啊.
You mean, he owned the entire water supply for the city?
你得一丝是，他曾经控制整个城市的水的供给？
- How'd they get it away from him? - Mulwray felt the public should own it.
- 那他们怎么把这个从他那里收回来的？ - 默瑞觉得应该由公众控制它。
Mr Mulwray? I thought you said Cross owned it.
默瑞先生？ 我以为你说的事克罗斯先生拥有它。
Along with Mr Mulwray.
跟默瑞先生一起。
- They were partners? - Yes, they were partners.
- 他们是拍档？ - 对，他们是拍档。
Mr Yelburton will see you now.
伊尔伯特先生现在要见你。
Mr Gittes, sorry to keep you waiting. These staff meetings just go on and on.
吉特斯先生，抱歉让你等了这么久。 总有一些乱七八糟的事情。
It must be especially tough to take over under these circumstances.
在这种情况下接任困难肯定特别多。
Yes, Hollis was the best department chief the city ever had.
是啊，霍利斯是本市各任部门 主席中最好的一个。
- What happened to your nose? - Cut myself shaving.
- 你的鼻子怎么了？ - 刮胡子的时候割到了。
- That must really smart. - Only when I breathe.
- 你得小心些，那一定很疼。 - 只有呼吸的时候。
Only when you breathe... Don't tell me you're still working for Mrs Mulwray?
只有你呼吸的时候…… 可别跟我说你还在为默瑞太太办事。
- I never was. - I don't understand.
- 我从来就没有过。 - 我不太明白。
Neither do I, actually. You hired me.
事实上，我也不太明白。 你雇佣的我。
Or you hired that chippie to hire me.
或者是你雇佣的那个妓女来雇佣我。
- You're not making a bit of sense. - Let's look at it this way:
- 吉特斯先生，你在说什么啊。 - 我们这样看：
Mulwray didn't want to build a dam. His reputation was hard to get around.
默瑞并不想修大坝。 而他的声誉又难以动摇
You decided to ruin it. Then he found out you were dumping water at night.
你打算毁了它。 然后他发现你每天晚上都在放水。
Then he was... drowned.
然后，他就……淹死了。
That's an outrageous accusation. I don't know what you're talking about.
吉特斯先生，这可是一项很严重的罪名。 我不知道你在说什么。
Well, Whitey Mehrholtz over at the Times will.
时代周刊的惠特尼.墨尔霍兹会知道的。
Dumping thousands of gallons of water in the middle of a drought is news.
在干旱期间每天排放成千加仑 的水会是一条新闻的。
Mr Gittes...
吉特斯先生……
We're not anxious for it to get around, but we have been diverting water -
我们并不担心这件事传出去， 但是我们调用那些水，是为了……
- to irrigate orange groves in the Northwest Valley.
灌溉西北流域的橘子园。
They have no legal right to our water, but we've been trying to help them out.
你知道，那边的农民没有我们这些水的合法使 用权，但我们希望能帮助他们解决困难。
When you divert water, there's a little run-off.
自然地，引水的时候，总难免有一些会流走。
Yeah, a little run-off... Where did you say those groves were?
对，一些会流走…… 你刚才说的树林在什么地方？
- In the Northwest Valley. - That's like saying they're in Arizona.
- 西北流域。 - 听起来好像他们在亚利桑那。
My field men are out, I can't give you the exact location.
我们负责地域的人不在， 恐怕我没办法给你一个确切的位置。
You're a married man, aren't you? Hard working, wife, kids...?
-你已经结婚了，是吗？    -对。 -工作努力，有老婆，孩子……？
- Yes. - I don't want to nail you.
- 对。 - 我不想拆穿你。
I want to find out who put you up to it. I'll give you a few days to think on it.
我只是想找出来是谁指使你的。 我给你几天的时间考虑。
Call me, I can help. Who knows, maybe we can put the whole thing off -
打电话给我，我会有用的。 谁知道呢，也许我们可以把整件事推托到几个大人物身上……
- on a few big shots, and you can stay head of the department for 20 years.
然后你就可以安安心心再当20年的部门主席。
- Drink? - No, thank you.
- 喝点什么？ - 不了，谢谢。
What is your usual salary?
你通常薪水多少？
$35 a day, plus 20 for my associates.
一天35美元，加上助手的20元
Plus expenses, plus a bonus if I show results.
加上日用开支， 如果有结果的话，还有奖金
Whoever killed my husband, why have they gone to all this trouble?
不管是谁杀了我的丈夫， 他们为什么要惹这么多事？
Money. How they plan to make it emptying reservoirs, I don't know.
为了钱。 至于他们为什么要清空水库，我不知道。
I'll pay your salary, plus $5,000, -
我会付给你薪水，另外再加5000美元……
- if you find out what happened to Hollis, and who is involved.
如果你能查出霍利斯究竟出了什么事， 以及还有谁跟这件事有牵连。
Sophie, draw up one of our standard contracts for Mrs Mulwray.
-苏菲，起草一份跟默瑞夫人之间的合同。 -好的，吉特斯先生。
Were you married before Mulwray and your father sold the water department?
跟我说说这些事……嗯，你是在默瑞还有你 父亲卖出水利部门以后才结婚的吗？
Noah Cross is your father, isn't he?
诺亚 克罗斯是你父亲，不是吗？
Yes, of course.
是，当然。
It was sometime after. I was just out of grade school when they did that.
过了一段时间以后。 他们卖的时候我才刚刚毕业。
Then you married your father's business partner.
然后你嫁给了你父亲的商业伙伴。
You've already got one going.
但是你实际上已经有男朋友了。
Does my talking about your father upset you?
是不是我关于父亲的这些话触犯到你了？
No...
没有……
Yes, a little. You see, Hollis and my fa...
是的，有点。 你知道，霍利斯跟我……
...my father had a falling out, finally.
我父亲，最终闹翻了。
- Over you or the water department? - Why should it be over me?
- 因为你还是水利部？ - 为什么是要因为我？
Then it was over the water department.
那就是因为水利部了。
Hollis felt the water should belong to the public. I think my father disagreed.
霍利斯觉得水应该是属于大家的。 我不认为我父亲那么想。
Actually, it was over the Van der Lip Dam. The dam that broke.
事实上，是因为范德利普大坝。 塌了的那个大坝。
- Hollis never forgave him for it. - Never forgave him for what?
- 霍利斯因为它不肯原谅他。 - 因为什么不原谅他？
For talking him into building it. They never spoke from that time on.
劝他修那个大坝。 从那以后他们就再也不说话了。
You sure about that?
你确定？
Of course I'm sure.
当然确定。
Sign here.
在这儿签字。
The copy's for you.
这份给你。
Mr Gittes? How do you do?
吉特斯先生？ 你好。
- You got a nasty reputation. I like that. - Thanks.
- 虽然你的名声并不太好，但我喜欢。 - 谢谢。
You're not a bank president. In your business it's good advertising.
你不是银行行长，在你那行， 这是个很好的广告
- It doesn't hurt. - It helps get a client like my daughter.
- 这没关系。 - 这样有助于吸引像我女儿那样的顾客。
- Probably. - I'm surprised you still work for her.
- 有可能。 - 我很奇怪于你仍然在为工作。
Unless she's suddenly come up with another husband.
难道她突然又有了一个丈夫？
She happens to think the last one was murdered.
她只是觉得自己的前夫是被谋杀的。
- How did she get that idea? - I think I gave it to her.
- 她为什么会这么想？ - 我想是我跟她说的。
I hope you don't mind. I believe they should be served with the head.
我希望你不要介意。 我觉得鱼头应该一起上。
As long as you don't serve the chicken that way.
还好。只要鸡不是这么上就行了。
Tell me, what do the police say?
跟我说说，警察是怎么说的？
They're calling it an accident.
他们说这是一个意外。
- Who's the investigating officer? - Lt. Lou Escobar.
- 调查官是谁？ - 卢 斯库巴。
- You know him? - Oh, yeah.
- 你认识他吗？ - 嗯，认识。
- Where from? - We worked together, in Chinatown.
- 从那来的？ - 我们以前在唐人街一起工作。
- Would you call him a capable man? - Very.
- 你觉得他能干吗？ - 很能干？
- Honest? - As far as it goes.
- 诚实吗？ - 就目前来说是。
He has to swim in the same water we all do.
他跟我们在一条河里游泳。
But there's no reason to think he's bungled the case?
那没理由他会把这件事办砸啊。
- Too bad. - Too bad?
- 太糟了 - 太糟了？
It makes me think you're taking my daughter for a ride, -
弄得我以为你想欺骗我的女儿，……
- financially speaking, of course.
当然，是在经济上。
What are you charging her?
你向她收多少钱？
My usual fee, plus a bonus if I get results.
跟平时一样，如果有结果的话， 还有奖金。
Are you sleeping with her?
你跟她睡过觉吗？
You have to think about that to remember?
你总不是还要想想才能记起来吧？
If you want an answer to that question, I'll put one of my men on the job.
如果你想要一个答案的话， 我会让我的手下去做。
- Good afternoon. - Mr Gittes...
- 祝您下午愉快 - 吉特斯先生……
She's just lost her husband. I don't want her taken advantage of.
她刚刚失去了丈夫， 我不想她被利用。
- Sit down. - What for?
- 请坐。 - 为什么？
You may think you know what you're dealing with, but believe me, you don't.
你可能觉得自己子到究竟在跟谁打交道， 可是相信我，你并不知道。
- Why is that funny? - The DA used to say that in Chinatown.
- 怎么会那么搞笑？ - 在唐人街的时候，检察官也常常那么说
Was he right?
他说的对吗？
Exactly what do you know about me? Sit down.
实际上你又了解我什么呢？ 坐下来。
You're rich, and too respectable to want your name in the newspapers.
总的来说，你很有钱，而且太有名望了而不 希望自己的名字出现在报纸上。
Of course I'm respectable. I'm old.
当然我很有名望。我老了。
Politicians, ugly buildings and whores get respectable if they last a long time.
那些政治家，那些丑陋的建筑，娼妓， 如果他们能做的久，也会很有名。
I'll double your fee and pay you $10,000 if you find Hollis's girlfriend.
如果你能找到霍利斯的女朋友的话， 我给你双倍的佣金，还有1万美元的奖励
- Girlfriend? - Disappeared, hasn't she?
- 女朋友？ - 她消失了，不是吗？ - 是啊。
- Wouldn't it be useful to talk to her? - Maybe.
- 跟她聊聊不是会很有用吗？ - 也许吧。
If he was murdered, she may be the last to see him alive.
如果他是被谋杀的，她也许是他生前 见到的最后一个人
When was the last time you saw him?
你最后一次见到他是什么时候？
Sheriff's gold posse. Damn fools.
是治安官的那一队人。一群白痴。
They paid $5,000 apiece toward the sheriff's re-election.
他们为了州长的再次当选每个人交了5000美元。
I let them practice up here.
我让他们来这儿联系。
- Do you know when you last saw him? - At my age you tend to forget.
- 你还记得上一次是什么时候见到的他吗？ - 到我这个年纪，有些事就记不住了
Five days ago, at the Pig & Whistle. You had one hell of an argument.
是在5年前，在酒馆外。 你们大吵了一架。
I got the pictures in my office, if that'll help you remember.
我办公室里有照片，也许它们能帮你想起来。
- What did you argue about? - My daughter.
- 你们在争论什么？ - 我女儿。
- What about her? - Just find the girl, Mr Gittes.
- 她的什么？ - 吉特斯，你只要找那个女孩就行了。
I know Hollis was fond of her. I'd like to help her if I can.
我知道霍利斯喜欢她。 如果可以的话，我希望能帮助她。
I had no idea you and Hollis were that fond of one another.
我以前不知道你跟霍利斯喜欢彼此。
Hollis Mulwray made this city, and he made me a fortune.
霍利斯 默瑞建造了这个城市， 也给我带了一笔财富。
We were a lot closer than Evelyn realised.
我们比伊夫林想象的要亲密的多。
If you want to hire me, I still have to know what the argument was about.
如果你想要雇用我，我还是 要知道你们在争论什么。
My daughter's very jealous. I didn't want her to find out about the girl.
我女儿嫉妒心很重。 我不想让她发现这个女孩的事。
- How did you find out? - I've still got a few friends in town.
- 你是怎么知道的？ - 我在镇子里有一些朋友。
Okay...
好吧……
I'll have my secretary draw up the papers.
我会让我的秘书起草协议。
Are you frightened for the girl or what Evelyn might do to her?
你是不是替那个女孩儿担心， 或者你觉得伊夫林会做些什么？
Just find the girl.
去找到那个女孩儿。
I'll look into it, as soon as I've checked out some orange groves.
一旦查清楚橘子园的事情，我就会调查的。
- Orange groves? - We'll be in touch, Mr Cross.
- 橘子园? - 再联系，克罗斯先生。
Could you tell me where the plat books for the Northwest Valley are?
请问西北流域的地图册放在什么地方？
Part of it's in Ventura County. We don't have them in our Hall of Records.
它有一部分在文特尔县。 我们档案馆里面没有这些资料。
Then I'll settle for L.A. County.
我只要洛杉矶郡的那部分资料。
Row 23, section C.
C区，23排。
Weasel.
推诿。
Sonny, why do they have all those names pasted in the plat books?
伙计，怎么书里面的名字都被粘起来了？
Land sales out of escrow are recorded within the week.
那里面记录了头几个星期卖地以后的契约。
- Then these are all new owners? - That's right.
- 那这些都是新的拥有者？ - 对啊。
That means that most of the Valley's sold in the last few months.
-也就是说这个流域的大部分土地在头几个月都卖了？ -就是这个意思。
Can I check one of these volumes out?
我能借一本书出去马？
This is not a lending library, it's the Hall of Records.
先生，这个地方不是图书馆，而是档案馆。
- How about a ruler? - A ruler?
- 那尺子呢? - 尺子?
The print's fine, and I left my glasses at home. I'd like to be able to read across.
这个字体很纤细，而我又把眼镜落在家里。 我想能好好读读。
I thank you.
非常感谢.
Hold it right there!
站那儿别动!
All right, quit it now! Search the man, see if he's armed.
好的，他妈的。 搜他的身，看他有没有带武器。
I didn't tell you to empty his pockets.
我不是让你掏他的口袋。
- Search him! - He ain't armed.
- 搜身搜身！ - 他没有武器。
Who are you with, the Water Department or the real estate office?
你跟谁一起的？水利部还是房地产公司？
Get away from me! Come near me with that again, you'll need a pair of them!
离我远点！你要是再拿着它靠近我， 你以后就要用双拐了！
- Pick on somebody your own size. - Give him a chance to say something.
- 先打量下自己再说吧！ - 让他说。
The name's Gittes, private investigator. I'm not with either one of them.
我是吉特斯，私家侦探。 不跟它们两个任何一个一伙。
What are you doing out here?
你来这儿干吗？
A client hired me to see if the Water Department was irrigating your land.
一个委托人让我来调查看看水利部 有没有灌溉你们的土地。
The Water Dept.'s been sending people out here to blow up my water tanks.
灌溉？水利部的人派人来炸我们的蓄水池。
They put poison in my wells. That's a funny way to irrigate.
在我的井里面下毒药。 这种灌溉方式未免太搞笑了吧？
Who'd hire you for a thing like that?
谁雇用你做这件事？
- Mrs Evelyn Mulwray. - That's the one who's done it to us.
- 伊夫林 默瑞夫人。 - 她就是那个这么对付我们的人。
Mulwray's dead. You don't know what you're talking about, you dumb Okie.
默瑞死了。你根本就不知道自己 在说什么，你这个笨蛋。
Well, that's that.
好了，行了。
What's going on?
发生什么事了？
You didn't look good. We thought we better call your employer.
你看起来不太好。 我们觉得叫你的雇主来比较合适。
Thanks for coming.
谢谢你过来。
That dam your husband opposed is a con job.
-那个大坝果然不应该建。-哪个大坝？ -你丈夫反对的那个。
They're conning L.A. Into building it, but the water's coming here, not to L.A.
他们对洛杉矶不利。如果建造的话， 水会来这里，而不是洛杉矶。
Everything you can see. All around us. I was at the Hall of Records today.
-来这个流域？ -你能看到这一切。我们 四周的一切。我今天去了档案馆。
In the last three months, Robert Knox has bought 7,000 acres.
在过去的三个月，罗伯特 诺克斯买 了7000英亩。
Emma Dill: 12,000. C. Speer: 5,000. Jasper Lamar Crabb: 25,000 acres.
艾玛 迪尔： 12,000； C. 斯波: 5,000. 杰斯皮尔 拉马尔 克拉波: 25,000 英亩
Jasper Lamar Crabb? I think I would have remembered that name.
杰斯皮尔 拉马尔 克拉波？ 我对这个名字有印象。
They're blowing the farmers out and then buying their land for peanuts.
他们把这些农民赶出去，然后买下 这些地方种花生。
You know what this land would be worth with a steady water supply?
你知道要是有稳定水源， 这块土地值多少钱吗？
About 30 million more than they paid for it.
比他们给的钱要多大约3千万。
- Hollis knew about this? - That's why he was killed.
- 霍利斯知道这件事？ - 所以他被杀了。
Jasper Lamar Crabb...
杰斯皮尔 拉马尔 克拉波……
- We got it. - What is it?
- 我知道了。 - 是什么？
"A memorial was held at the Mar Vista Inn for Jasper Lamar Crabb."
“在 玛 维斯塔旅馆为杰斯皮尔 拉马尔 克拉波举行追悼仪式”
- He passed away two weeks ago. - Is that unusual?
- 他两周前死了。 - 很不寻常吗？
He passed away two weeks ago. One week ago he bought the land.
他两星期前死了。 却在一周前买了土地。
That's unusual.
这不正常。
Hello, I'm Mr Palmer. Can I help you folks?
你好，我是帕莫先生。 有什么我能帮忙的吗？
Yes, I hope so.
是的，我希望是这样。
- It's Dad. I can't handle him anymore. - My goodness.
- 是我爸爸。我再也不能照顾他了…… - 我的天啊。
- It's nothing with Dad, it's me. - Dad's an angel with everyone else.
- 他没事，是我。 - 爸爸是其他所有人的守护神。
- But when he and my h... - I don't know.
- 但是他跟我…… - 我不知道。
Of course, I'm anxious for him to have the best. Money is no object.
当然，我希望他得到最好的。钱不是问题。
- Perhaps if we met with your father. - There is one question...
- 也许我们应该见见你的父亲。 - 只有一个问题……
Do you accept people of the Jewish persuasion?
你们接受犹太教的人吗？
- I'm sorry, but we don't. - Neither does Dad. We had to be sure.
- 我很抱歉，但是我们不接受。 - 我爸爸也是。我们需要确定一下。
Would it be possible to see a list of your patients, just to be certain?
再确定一下，别人能看到你们病人的名单吗？
We never reveal the names of our guests. It's policy.
我们从不泄露来宾的名单。这是政策。
- You'd agree if your father lived here. - Exactly what I wanted to hear you say.
- 你会同意让你父亲住在这里的。 - 这正是我想听到的。
- Is it too late for us to look around? - No, allow me to show you.
- 我们现在四处看看会不会太晚？ - 不晚，我来领你们参观。
- Could we stroll on our own? - Yes, if you stay in the main building.
- 我们自己随便走走可以吗？ - 可以，不过只能在主建筑区。
- It's almost bedtime. - We understand.
- 快要到睡觉时间了。 - 我们理解。
Come, my sweet.
来吧，亲爱的。
Charley, you ought to know better than that.
查理，你应该知道的更多的。
They're all there. Every goddam name.
都在那儿。每一个该遭诅咒的名字。
You're looking at the owners of a 50,000 acre empire.
你看到的是5万英亩土地的拥有者。
They may not know it, but they are.
他们也许不知道，可他们的确是。
Hello, girls.
嗨，女士们。
Are any of you Emma Dill?
你们哪一位是艾玛 迪尔？
Are you Emma?
-你是艾玛？ -是吗？
- I've wanted to meet you a long time. - Why?
- 我很早就已经想见你了。 - 为什么？
- Did you know you were very wealthy? - I'm not.
- 难道你不知道自己很有钱吗？ - 我可没有。
- You own a lot of land. - No more.
- 我有一大块土地。 - 已经不再有了。
Some time ago, my late husband owned a lot of beach property, -
不久前，我最后一个丈夫拥有一块海滩……
- but we lost it.
但是我们失去了它。
That's very beautiful. Where did you get this piece of material?
这个很漂亮。 你们从哪里弄到这块布料？
At the Albacore Club.
在海鱼俱乐部。
Albacore. It's a fish.
海鱼。这是一种鱼。
My grandson is a member. They take very nice care of us.
我的孙子是会员。 他们对我们很好。
- How do they do that? - Give us things. Not just a flag, but...
- 他们都怎么做呢？ - 给我们东西。不仅仅是旗，还有……
- But what? - We're an unofficial charity to them.
- 还有什么？ - 对于他们，我们是一个非官方的慈善组织。
Would you come with me? Someone wants to talk with you.
请跟我来好吗？ 有人想跟你谈谈。
Goodbye, ladies.
-女士们，再见。 -再见
I want you to meet someone, Gittes.
我想让你见一个人，吉特斯。
- Can we leave the lady out of this? - Yeah, why not.
- 能不能让这位女士置身事外。 - 是的，当然
- I'd like to see her to the car. - She knows where it's at.
- 我把她送到车上。 - 她知道车在哪儿。
- I'll stay. - Get in the car.
- 我要留下来。 - 去车里。
Maid's night off?
女仆晚上都不上班？
- Why? - Because nobody's here, that's why.
- 怎么了？ - 因为没人在。这就是怎么了。
I gave everyone the night off.
每个人晚上都不用工作
- Easy, it's an innocent question. - No question from you is innocent.
- 放轻松点，这只是个单纯的问题 - 你的问题没有一个是单纯的。
I guess you're right.
也许你是对的。
To you, Mrs Mulwray.
敬你，默瑞夫人
Frankly, tonight you saved my a... you saved my neck.
坦白说，你今晚救了... 你救了我的命。
Tell me, Mr Gittes, does this often happen to you?
告诉我，吉特斯先生， 对于你，这种事是不是经常发生？
What's that?
什么意思？
I'm judging only on part of today, but if this is how you go about your work, -
我只是根据今天的这些事来推断，但是 如果你就是这样工作的话……
- I'd say you'd be lucky to get through a whole day.
我得说，你能活到今天真幸运。
- This hasn't happened for a long time. - When was the last time?
- 有很久不是这样了。 - 上一次是什么时候？
- Why? - It's an innocent question.
- 怎么了？ - 只是个单纯的问题。
- In Chinatown. - What were you doing there?
- 在唐人街。 - 你在那儿干什么？
- Working for the District Attorney. - Doing what?
- 给检察官工作。 - 做什么？
- As little as possible. - The DA gives you advice like that?
- 尽可能的什么也不做。 - 检察官给你这样的建议吗？
They do in Chinatown.
在唐人街，的确是这样
Why did you leave the police force?
你为什么要离开警察部门呢？
Do you have any peroxide, or anything like that?
你有没有一些双氧水，或者类似的东西？
Surely. Come this way.
当然。这边来。
God!
天哪！
That's a nasty cut.
这伤口真可怕。
I had no idea.
我都不知道
Sorry!
对不起。
Is it painful?
痛不痛？
It must be painful.
肯定痛
- What's wrong? - Your eye.
- 怎么了？ - 你的眼睛。
What about it?
怎么了？
There's something black in the green part of your eye.
你眼睛的蓝色部分中有黑色的东西。
Oh, that. It's a flaw in the iris.
哦，那个。 是虹膜上的一点瑕疵。
- A flaw? - Yes, it's a sort of birthmark.
- 瑕疵？ - 对，是胎记之类的东西。
- Did you wear a uniform? - Sometimes.
- 你以前穿制服吗？ - 有时候。
You must have looked cute in blue.
你穿蓝色肯定很帅。
Give me a break, will you?
让我休息一下，好吗？
I want to know more about you.
我想多了解你一些。
Not now.
不是现在。
You really don't like to talk about the past, do you?
你当真不喜欢谈论过去，是吗？
I'm tired.
我累了。
- Why does it bother you to talk of it? - It bothers everybody who works there.
-为什么谈论过去你让你这么烦呢？ - 每个在那儿工作的人都烦。
- Where? - Chinatown. Everybody.
- 哪儿？ - 唐人街。每个人。
- To me it was just bad luck. - Why?
- 对我来说，真的是倒霉。 - 为什么？
You can't always tell what's going on.
你总是不知道会发生什么事。
Like with you.
就像跟你在一起一样。
Why was... Why was it bad luck?
为什么…… 为什么会是霉运？
I was trying to keep someone from being hurt.
我努力保护某个人不受到伤害。
I ended up making sure that she was hurt.
可是最后却一定会让她受伤。
Cherchez la femme.
跟女人有关.
Was there a woman involved?
是不是也有一个女人牵扯其中？
Of course.
当然。
Dead?
死了吗？
Yes, hello?
是，喂？
Oh, my God! Don't do anything.
哦，天哪。 什么都别做。
Don't do anything until I get there.
在我过去之前什么都别做。
I have to go.
我得走了。
- Where? - It's just that I have to.
- 去哪儿？ - 是我必须要去的地方。
- I want to know where you're going. - Don't be angry.
- 我想知道你去哪儿。 - 别生气。
It has nothing to do with you or any of this.
这件事跟你，跟这一切都没有关系。
- Where are you going? - Please...
- 你去哪儿？ - 求求你……
Trust me this much.
请相信我。
I'll be back.
我会回来。
There is something that I should tell you -
有些事情我要告诉你……
- about the fishing club that old lady mentioned.
是关于那位老太太提到的俱乐部的。
- The Albacore Club. - It has to do with my father.
- 海鱼俱乐部。. - 它跟我父亲有关系。
- I know. - He owns it... You know?
- 我知道。 - 他拥有它……你知道？
I saw him.
我见到他了。
You saw... my father?
你见到……我父亲了？
- When? - This morning.
- 什么时候？ - 今天早上。
- You didn't tell me. - Well, there hasn't been much time.
- 你并没有告诉我。 - 恩，没有那么多的时间。
What did he say?
他说什么了？
- What did he say? - That you were jealous.
- 他说什么了？ - 说你嫉妒。
- That he was afraid what you might do. - To whom?
- 说他担心你会做些什么。 - 针对谁？
Mulwray's girlfriend, for one.
默瑞的女朋友，那一个。
He wanted to know where she was.
他想知道她在那儿。
I want you to listen to me. My father is a very dangerous man.
我想你听我说。 我父亲是一个很危险的人。
You don't know how dangerous. You don't know how crazy.
你不知道他有多危险。 你不知道他有多疯狂。
Are you trying to tell me that he might be behind all of this?
你打算跟我说他就是这一切的幕后者？
It's possible.
这是有可能的。
- Even the death of your husband? - It's possible.
- 甚至你丈夫的死？ - 有可能。
Now please, don't ask me any more questions. Just wait for me here.
好了，拜托，不要再问我问题了。 在这儿，等我回来。
I need you here.
我需要你在这儿。
- Give me the keys. - You...!
- 把钥匙给我。 - 你……！
It's either that or you drive yourself to the police.
要么这样，要么你自己开车去警察局。
Come on, Mrs Mulwray. You have your husband's girlfriend tied up in there.
- 警察局？ - 默瑞夫人，你把你丈夫的女朋友绑在那里。
- She's not tied up. - You're holding her against her will.
- 她没有被绑起来。 - 你知道我的意思。你逆着她的意愿拘留她。
I am not.
我没有。
- Okay, then let's go talk to her. - No!
- 那好吧，我们进去跟她谈谈。 - 不！
She's too upset.
她太生气了。
- What about? - Hollis's death.
- 因为什么？ - 霍利斯的死。
I tried to keep it from her until I could make plans for us to leave.
我试图对她隐瞒这件事，直到 我们做好打算离开。
She just found out about it?
她刚刚才知道？
- That's not what it looks like. - What does it look like?
- 看起来不太像。 - 看起来像什么？
Like she knows more than you want her to tell.
看起来，她知道比你想让她说的多。
- You're insane. - Tell me the truth. I'm not the police.
- 你有神经病。 - 跟我说实话，我不是警察。
I don't care what you've done. I don't want to hurt you.
我不管你做过什么。 我不想伤害你。
- You won't go to the police if I tell you? - I will if you don't.
- 如果我告诉你你不会去报警吗？ - 如果你不说，我会。
She's my sister.
她是我的妹妹。
Take it easy.
放松点。
If she's your sister, she's your sister.
如果她是你的妹妹，她就是你的妹妹。
- Why all the secrecy? - I can't...
- 为什么要保密呢？ - 我不能……
Is it because she was seeing your husband? Is that it?
就是因为她跟你的丈夫幽会？是这样吗？
I'd never have harmed Hollis.
我从来没有伤害过霍利斯。
He was the most gentle, decent man imaginable.
他是所能想象的最绅士，最正派的人。
And he put up with more from me than you'll ever know.
而且他所忍受我的远远比你知道的要多。
I wanted him to be happy.
我希望他开心。
I borrowed you husband's car. I'll bring it back in the morning.
我借用了你丈夫的车。 早上我会放回去。
- Aren't you coming back with me? - Don't worry, I won't tell anybody.
- 你不跟我一起回去？ - 别担心，我不会跟任何人说的。
That's not what I meant.
我不是那个意思。
Yeah, well...
是的，嗯……
I'm tired, Mrs Mulwray. Good night.
我累了，默瑞夫人。晚安。
Gittes? Gittes?
吉特斯？吉特斯？
- Yeah? - Ida Sessions wants to see you.
- 嗯？ - 艾达 瑟莘想见你。
- Who? - Ida Sessions. You remember Ida.
- 谁？ - 艾达 瑟莘。还记得艾达吧？
- Yeah, I do...? - Sure you do.
- 对，我记得…… - 你当然记得。
I'll tell you what, pal...
我跟你说，伙计……
If Ida wants to see me, she can call me at my office.
如果艾达想见我，她可以打电话到我的办公室。
8481/2 East Kensington, Echo Park.
埃克公园，8481/2 东肯辛顿
She begged me to call. She's waiting for you.
她求我给你打电话。 她在等你。
Find anything interesting, Gittes?
发现什么了吗，吉特斯？
- What are you doing around here? - Didn't you call me?
- 你在这儿干什么？ - 你没有跟我打电话吗？
- How come you happen to know her? - I don't.
- 你怎么认识她？ - 我不认识。
I want to show you something.
我想给你看点东西。
- Isn't that your phone number? - I forget, I don't call myself that often.
- 这不是你的电话吗？ - 我忘了，我不经常给自己打电话。
Just to make sure, we had Loach give you a call.
只是想确定一下， 我们让罗克给你打了电话
What happened to your nose? Get a bedroom window slammed on it?
你的鼻子怎么了？ 被卧室的窗子打到了吗？
Nope. Your wife got excited, she crossed her legs a little too quick.
不是。你老婆太兴奋了，她并腿太快了。
- They look familiar? - Yeah, I took them. So what?
- 眼熟吗？ - 对，我照的，怎么了？
- How did she happen to have them? - Either you tell me or I guess.
- 她怎么会有这些照片？ - 你告诉我，或者让我猜。
- Do you really think I'm stupid? - Let me think on it. I'll get back to you.
- 你真的觉得我傻吗？ - 让我想想。我会回来找你。
- Now I'd like to go home. - I want the other pictures.
- 现在我想回家了。 - 我想要其它的照片。
This broad hired you, not Evelyn Mulwray.
这个女人雇佣的你， 而不是伊夫琳 默瑞。
Somebody wanted to shake Mulwray down.
有人想把默瑞整下台。
She hired you. That's how you found out he was murdered.
她雇用的你。所以你发现他是被谋杀的。
- I heard it was an accident. - You think we're a bunch of assholes?
- 我听说那是一个意外。 - 你当我们是白痴吗？
Mulwray had salt water in his lungs.
默瑞的肺部有盐水。
You tailed him day and night. You saw who killed him. You even took pictures.
你日夜跟踪他。你看到了是谁杀的他， 你甚至拍了照片。
It was Evelyn Mulwray. She's been paying you off ever since.
是伊夫琳 默瑞。 从那个时候起她就开始给你钱。
You accuse me of extortion? You're dumber than you think I think you are.
你要控告我勒索？ 你比你认为的我所想象中的你还要白痴。
I wouldn't extort a nickel from my worst enemy.
我不会从我最糟糕的敌人那儿勒索一分钱的。
I want the pictures. Accessory after the fact, conspiracy and extortion.
我想要照片。 我们谈论的是犯罪以后，包庇罪犯， 共谋还有敲诈。
You think Evelyn killed her husband in the ocean, -
你认为伊夫琳 默瑞在海里面杀死 了她的丈夫……
- then dragged him up to a reservoir to make it look more like an accident?
然后把他拉到水库，好让这一切看起来 像是一个意外。
He was moved because somebody didn't want his body found in the ocean.
别人移动他是因为不想让他的尸体 在海里被发现。
He found out they were dumping water and trying to cover it up.
他发现他们在放水。他们试图想掩盖这件事。
- What the hell are you talking about? - Come on, I'll show you.
- 你他妈到底在说什么？ - 得了，我带你看。
Come on, Lou, you're in charge. Make a decision.
快点，卢，你是负责人。 作决定吧。
It's too late. They only dump the water at night.
-太晚了。 -什么太晚了？ -他们只在晚上放水。
- Reach anybody? - Yelburton. He's the new chief.
- 联系到什么人了吗？ - 伊尔博坦。他是新的主管。
- I know. Go on. - He says...
- 我知道。继续。 - 他说……
- I know what he says. - Shut up! Go on.
- 我知道他说什么。 - 闭嘴。继续！
He says there's irrigation in the Valley, and there's always a little run-off.
他说是在浇灌山谷那一片，总有一些水流失的。
He says Gittes knows this, and that he's made irresponsible accusations.
他说吉特斯知道这些，他做了一些 不负责任的指控。
Let's get a warrant for her arrest. What are we waiting for?
我们申请她的逮捕令。 我们还在等什么？
He just made lieutenant. He wants to hang on to his little gold bar.
他才刚当上中尉。 他只是想紧紧抓住那块小肩章。
Have her in my office in two hours. Remember, I don't have to let you go.
让她在我办公室呆两个小时。 记得，我不必让你走。
I've got you right now for withholding evidence.
我现在因为藏匿证据而扣留你。
Where's Mrs Mulwray? Are these her bags?
默瑞夫人在那儿？ 这些是不是她的包？
Is she going on a trip?
她准备去旅游？
What going on here? Is she going on a vacation?
发生什么事了？ 她要去度假？
- Mrs Mulwray no home. - Well, I'll just have a look around.
- 默瑞夫人不在家。 - 好吧，我四处看看。
- Yeah, bad for the glass. - Yes, bad for glass.
- 对，对水草不好。
Salt water very bad for glass.
盐水对水草很不好。
Salt water?
盐水？
Very, very bad. See?
非常，非常不好。看到了？
What's that?
那是什么？
Right there.
在那边。
There.
那边。
- You wait.
- 你等等。
How are you? I've been calling you.
你好吗？我一直都在跟你打电话。
- Have you slept? - Sure.
- 你睡着了吗？ - 当然。
Have you had lunch?
吃过午饭了吗？
- Where's the girl? - Upstairs. Why?
- 那个女孩儿呢？ - 楼上。怎么了？
- I want to see her. - She's having a bath right now.
- 我想见见她。 - 她在洗澡。
- Why do you want to see her? - Going someplace?
- 怎么想见他？ - 要出去？
Yes, we have a 5:30 train to catch.
对，我们要赶5：30的火车。
Jake...
喂……
J.J. Gittes for Lt. Escobar.
J.J. 吉特斯，找Lt. Escobar.
- What's wrong? I said we have a 5:30... - You're gonna miss your train.
- 发生什么事了？我说过我们5：30…… - 你赶不上火车了。
Lou, meet me at 1972 Canyon Drive.
卢，在1972 Canyon Drive见我。
Yeah, as soon as you can.
对，越快越好。
- Why did you do that? - You know any criminal lawyers?
- 你为什么要这么做？ - 你认识什么负责刑事案件的律师吗？
- No. - No worry, I can recommend a couple.
- 不。 - 别担心，我帮你介绍两个。
They're expensive, but you can afford it.
比较贵，但是你能出得起。
Will you please tell me what this is all about?
你能行行好告诉我到底是怎么回事吗？
I found these in your backyard, in the pond.
我在你家后院的池塘里发现了这个。
They belonged to your husband, didn't they?
是你丈夫的，不是吗？不是吗？
- I don't know. Yes, probably. - Positively. He was drowned there.
- 我不知道。是，有可能。 - 肯定是。他在那儿淹死的。
- What? - There's no time to be shocked.
- 什么？ - 没时间对事实感到震惊了。
The coroner proved he had salt water in his lungs when he was killed.
验尸官发现他的肺里面有盐水。
I want to know how it happened, and why, -
我想在埃斯科巴到这儿之前，……
- before Escobar gets here. I don't want to lose my license.
……搞清这事怎么回事，还有为什么。 我不想丢了自己的执照。
I don't know what you are talking about. This is the craziest...
我不知道你在说什么。 这是最疯狂……
Stop it! I want to make it easy for you. You were jealous, you had a fight.
别说了！我来帮你理顺， 你嫉妒她，所以你们打架了。
He hit his head. It was an accident. But his girl is a witness.
他撞倒了头。这是个意外。 但那个女孩是目击证人。
So you had to shut her up, and you had the money to do it.
所以你得让她闭嘴，而且你有这笔钱。
- Yes or no? - No!
- 是不是？ - 不是！
Who is she? She's not your sister, you don't have one.
她是谁？她不是你的妹妹！ 你没有妹妹！
I'll tell you the truth.
我会告诉你真相。
Good. What's her name?
很好。她叫什么名字？
- Katherine. - Katherine who?
- 凯瑟琳。 - 凯瑟琳什么？
She's my daughter.
她是我的女儿。
- I said I want the truth! - She's my sister.
- 我说我要真相。 - 她是我的妹妹。
She's my daughter. My sister, my daughter.
她是我的女儿。 我妹妹，我女儿。
I said I want the truth!
我说过我要事实真相！
She's my sister and my daughter!
她是我的妹妹和女儿！
Khan, please, go back. For God's sake, keep her upstairs.
克汉,求求你，回去。 看在上帝的份上，让她呆在楼上。
My father and I...
我父亲跟我……
Understand? Or is it too tough for you?
明白了吗？ 或者这个对于你太困难了？
He raped you?
他强奸了你？
- Then what happened? - I ran away.
- 然后呢？ - 我逃跑了。
To Mexico?
去了墨西哥。
Hollis came and took care of me.
霍利斯来了，照顾我。
I couldn't see her. I was 15.
我不能见她。我只有15岁。
I wanted to but I... I couldn't.
我想但是我…… 我不能
Then...
然后……
Now I want to be with her. I want to take care of her.
现在我想跟她一起。 我想照顾她。
- Where are you gonna take her now? - Back to Mexico.
- 你想带她去那儿？ - 回到墨西哥。
You can't take the train. Escobar will be looking for you everywhere.
你不能坐火车。 埃斯科巴会四处找你的。
- How about a plane? - That's worse.
- 飞机呢？ - 那更糟。
You betterjust go. Leave all this stuff here. Where does Khan live?
你最好走吧。把这都留在这儿。 克汉住那儿？
- Get the exact address. - All right.
- 要确切的地址。 - 好。
Those didn't belong to Hollis.
这不是霍利斯的。
- How do you know? - He didn't wear bifocals.
- 你怎么知道？ - 他不戴双焦距的。
- Katherine, say hello to Mr Gittes. - Hello.
- 凯瑟琳，跟吉特斯先生打招呼。 - 你好。
Hello.
你好。
He lives at 1712 Alameda. Do you know where that is?
他住在1712号0大道。 你知道是哪儿吗？
Sure.
当然。
Sophie, get me Walsh.
苏菲，给我找一下沃尔什。
Listen pal, Escobar's gonna try and book me in about five minutes.
听着伙计，埃斯科巴可能会在5分钟之内 过来控告我。
- What's the matter? - Relax and I'll tell you.
- 发生什么事了？ - 放松点，我会跟你说的。
If you don't hear from me in two hours, you and Duffy come to 1712 Alameda.
如果两个小时以后你还没有我的消息话， 你跟达菲就去1712大道。
- Jesus, that's in Chinatown, aint it? - I know where it is. Just do it.
- 天哪，是在唐人街，不是吗？ - 我知道是在哪儿。就这么做。
Come on in, Lou.
进来，卢。
Looks like we're both too late. She flew the coop.
看起来我们都晚了。她已经离开了。
And you've no idea where she went?
你不知道她去哪儿？
As a matter of fact I do. Her maid's house. She knows something's up.
事实上，我知道。她女仆的家。 她知道一些事情。
What's the maid's address?
那个女仆家在哪儿？
- She lives in Pedro. I'll write it down... - No, Gittes, you're gonna show us.
- 在普渡。我写下来…… - 不，吉特斯，你带我们去。
What for?
为什么？
Because if she ain't there, you're gonna stay downtown until she does show up.
因为如果她不在的话，你就得一直待到 她出现为止。
Gee Lou, I'm doing the best I can.
好吧，卢，我尽力。
Tell us about it on the way to San Pedro.
告诉我们去圣 普渡的路上。
- Let's get the little lady. - Can I ask you a favour?
- 我们去抓那个女人。 - 能帮个忙吗？
I'd like to bring her out myself.
我想自己带她出来。
She's not armed, she won't be a problem.
她不会有武器的，不会有什么问题。
I just want a minute alone with her. It would mean a lot to her, and to me.
我只是想跟她单独呆一会儿。 这对她，对我都很重要。
You never learn, do you, Jake?
你从来都不会吸取教训，是吗，吉特斯？
I guess not.
我想不是。
Okay...
好吧……
I'll give you three minutes. Just three minutes.
我给你三分钟。 只有三分钟。
Gee, thanks, Lou.
恩，谢谢你，卢。
Hello.
嗨。
Mr Gittes, come in! This is some surprise.
吉特斯先生，进来！ 太意外了。
- Call me Jake. How you doing, Curly? - Care to join us?
- 叫我杰克。你好吗，克利？ - 有兴趣加入我们吗？
- No, thanks. - A glass of wine? This is the fella...
- 不了，谢谢。 - 一杯酒？这个是那个……
- I know. - No, thank you.
- 我知道。 - 不，谢谢。
But I'd like a glass of water. Come out in the kitchen with me.
不过我想喝一杯水。 跟我来厨房把。
- Curly, where's your car? - In the garage off the alley.
- 克利，你的车在哪儿？ - 路那边的车库里。
Can you give me a ride somewhere...? Right now. It can't wait.
能不能载我一段……？ 就现在。我不能能再等了。
- I'll tell my wife. - Tell her later, Curl.
- 我得告诉我妻子。 - 以后再告诉她，克利。
Just drive slow for a block or two.
头一两个街区开慢一点。
- What's this all about? - I'll tell you in a block or two.
- 到底发生什么事了？ - 我一会儿告诉你。
- How much do you owe me? - Gee, we're going out tomorrow.
- 你欠我多少钱？ - 这个，我们明天要出船。
You've been good about it, but my cousin's sick.
你一直都很好，但是我的表弟病了。
How would you like to pay me off by taking two passengers to Encenada?
你愿不愿意用带两个人去安森达 来抵消你的钱？
- You'd have to leave tonight. - I don't know.
- 必须要今晚走。 - 我不知道。
I might be able to squeeze 75 bucks out of it for you.
我也许还可以省出75美元给你。
Maybe even 100.
甚至100。
- Plus what I owe? - I'll throw that in too.
- 加上我欠的？ - 我会把这些加进去。
1712 Alameda. Wait for me until 8:30. If I don't show, take them to your boat.
1712号大街。等我到8：30。 如果我没有出现的话，把她们带到你的船上。
You're sure this is okay?
你确定这样行吗？
Do you know how long I've been in this business?
你知道我在这行做了多久吗？
Have you got your checkbook handy, Mr Cross? I've got the girl.
你把支票本准备好了吗，克罗斯先生？ 我找到那个女孩了。
- You've got her? Where? - Remember the figures we discussed?
- 你找到了？在哪儿？ - 还记得我们定的价钱吗？
- Yes. Where are you? - Your daughter's house.
- 是的。你在哪儿？ - 你女儿家。
- How soon can you get here? - An hour.
- 你什么时候能过来？ - 一个小时。
There you are! Well, you don't look too much the worse for wear.
你在这儿！ 哦，你穿的怎么真是糟的不再糟了。
- Where's the girl? Is she all right? - She's fine.
- 女孩在哪儿？她还好吗？ - 很好。
- Well, where is she? - With her mother.
- 那么，她在哪儿？ - 跟她妈妈一起。
- I've got something I'd like to show you. - What is it?
- 我有一些东西想给你看。 - 是什么？
An obituary column. Can you see all right in this light?
讣告栏。 你这样能看得清楚吗？
I guess I can manage.
我想能行。
- What does it mean? - That you killed Hollis Mulwray.
- 什么意思？ - 意思是，你杀死了霍利斯 默瑞。
Right here. In that pond.
就在这儿，在池塘里。
You drowned him, and you left these.
你淹死了他，把眼镜落在了这里。
The coroner's report shows Mulwray had salt water in his lungs.
验尸官的报告表明他的肺里面有盐水。
Hollis was always fascinated by tide pools.
霍利斯总是对潮水洼很着迷。
- You know what he used to say? - I haven't the faintest idea.
- 你知道他过去经常怎么说吗？ - 我一点点都不知道。
'That's where life begins, tide pools!"
“潮水洼，生命开始的地方！”
He figured that if you dumped water into the desert sand -
他说，如果你把水倒进沙漠……
- and let it percolate down to the bedrock, -
……让它过滤到基岩……
- it wouldn't evaporate the way it does in reservoirs. You lose 20%, not 80%.
这样它们就不会像在水库那样蒸发掉。 只会损失20%，而不是80%。
- He made this city! - You were gonna do that in the Valley?
- 他建了这座城市！ - 你原打算在流域地区这样做？
I am doing it. When the bond issue passes Tuesday -
我一直都在这么做。 星期二协议一通过……
- there will be eight million dollars to build a reservoir.
就会有8百万美元可以用来造水库。
People will be mad when they find out they're paying for water they won't get.
人们一旦发现他们交了钱却没有水用， 会疯了的。
That's all taken care of. You see, -
会有人处理的。你看……
- either you bring the water to L.A. Or you bring L.A. To the water.
要么你把水带到洛杉矶， 要么你把洛杉矶带到水边。
- How are you gonna do that? - I'll incorporate the Valley into the city.
- 你打算怎么做？ - 我要把流域地区合并到城里里面。
- How much are you worth? - How much do you want?
- 你值多少钱？ - 你想要多少钱？
- Are you worth over ten million? - Oh, yes.
- 我只是想知道你值多少钱？1000多万？ - 哦，也许是的。
Why are you doing it? What can you buy that you can't already afford?
你为什么要这样？ 你已经付不起钱了还能买什么？
The future, Mr Gittes. The future.
未来，吉特斯先生。未来。
Now where's the girl? I want the only daughter I've got left.
那女孩在哪儿？ 我想找到我唯一留下的女儿。
As you now, Evelyn was lost to me a long time ago.
正如你所知，我很早就失去依夫琳了。
- Who do you blame for that? Her? - I don't blame myself.
- 这你能怪谁呢？她？ - 我不会责怪自己。
Most people never have to face the fact -
大部分人从来不面对这个事实……
- that at the right time and the right place, they're capable of anything.
就是在合适的时间，何时的地方， 他们可以做任何事情。
Claude, take those glasses from him.
克劳德，把这眼镜拿走。
Not worth it, Mr Gittes.
这不值得，吉特斯先生。
It's really not worth it.
真的不值。
Take us to the girl.
带我们去见那个女孩。
You remember Night Train Claude Mulvihill? These are my associates...
还记得夜间列车吗，克劳德 莫威黑尔? 这是我的助手。
- You're under arrest, Jake. - Good news.
- 你被捕了，杰克。 - 好消息。
Withholding evidence, extortion, accessory after the fact.
隐藏证据，勒索，窝藏嫌犯。
I didn't extort nothing from nobody. This is Noah Cross. Evelyn's father.
我没有从任何人那里勒索过任何东西。 这是诺亚 克罗斯，依夫琳的父亲。
He's the bird you're after. I can explain everything in five minutes. He's rich!
他才是你要抓的儿呢。我可以在五分钟之内 解释每一件事情。他很有钱！
- He thinks he can get away with it. - You shut up, or I'll lock you up.
- 他以为有钱就可以逃脱处罚。 - 你闭嘴，否则我把你扣起来。
I am rich, I am Noah Cross. Evelyn Mulwray is my daughter.
我很有钱，我是诺亚 克罗斯。 依夫琳 默瑞是我的女儿。
He's crazy, Lou! He killed Mulwray because of the water thing. Just listen!
他是疯子，卢！他为了水的事杀了默瑞。 你好好听我说5分钟，好吗？！
- Lock him to the wheel of the car. - You don't know what's going on here.
- 把他锁在车轮子上。 - 你不知道这儿会发生什么事。
Katherine!
凯瑟琳！
I am your grandfather, my dear. I am your grandfather.
我是你的祖父，亲爱的。 我是你的祖父。
No, go on. I'll follow you.
不，你们走。 我会跟着她。
- Get away from her. Get away! - Evelyn, please... be reasonable.
- 离开她！离开她！ - 依夫琳，拜托……理智一点。
- Come to my... - Get away from her!
- 到我的…… - 快离开她！
How many years have I got? She's mine, too.
我已经等了多久了？ 她也是我的！
She's never going to know that.
她永远都不要知道那些！
You're a disturbed woman. You cannot provide...
你是个不正常的女人。 你没有能力提供……
- Evelyn, let the police handle this. - He owns the police!
- 依夫琳，交给警察处理…… - 警察局是他的！
- Get away from her. - You'll have to kill me first.
- 快离开她！ - 那你得先杀了我。
Close the door.
关上门。
Halt!
停下！
Get the captain. Get an ambulance. Turn them all loose.
快叫上尉。叫救护车。 给他们松绑。
Lord... Oh, Lord!
罗德……哦，罗德
- As little as possible. - What's that?
- 尽可能的少。 - 你说什么。
What's that?
什么意思。
You wanna do your partner a big favour?
你想帮你的拍档你个大忙吗？
Take him home.
带他回家。
Just get him the hell out of here!
带他回家！ 让他离开这个地方！
Go home, Jake. I'm doing you a favour.
回家吧，杰克。 我是在帮你。
Come on, Jake.
快点，杰克。
Forget it, Jake. It's Chinatown.
忘了它吧，杰克。这里是唐人街。
All right, clear the area! On the sidewalk.
好吧，把这儿弄干净。 到人行道上去。
On the sidewalk!
到人行道上去！
Get off the street!
离开街道！